# Matthew Maslen

## **Front End Developer**

New to web development, with a background in animation - I have a keen eye for detail and a desire to learn new skills, continuously developing a better understanding of how things work.

Intrigued at the possibilities offered by animation and interactivity in the world of development, I'm excited to explore the ways information and user experience can be shaped by animated content.

• 07854070538 • email • github • portfolio

**Skills** 

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript (Vanilla & DOM), Object

Orientated PHP

Frameworks: React / Redux, Laravel

**Tooling:** Git, npm, Chrome Developer Tools, VS Code, pair programming,

Vagrant, Gulp, TDD, wireframing with Balsamiq

**Programming:** types, variables, functions, data structures

**Server-side:** MySQL, database migrations, APIs, templating with Blade,

**Interpersonal:** teamworking, conflict resolution, problem solving, decision

making

**Projects** 

#### **AutoTeam**

HTML, CSS, JS, React / Redux

DevelopMe technical challenge brief to create some kind of App or web App that randomly selects two 5-A-Side football teams from a list of 10 names.

Link | Code

#### Portfolio site

HTML & CSS

My personal portfolio website. Made using HTML and CSS techniques that I have learned during my time on the DevelopMe bootcamp.

Link | Code

#### **Education**

#### **Develop Me / Full Stack Software Development**

SEPTEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2020, Bristol / Remote

Intensive project-driven 12 week software development on the webstack course, taught by industry professionals using best practice approaches.

#### **BA(hons)** / Animation (Computer animation)

SEPTEMBER 2004 - JUNE 2007, Glamorgan University (GCADT)

### **Employment History**

#### Funko Animation Studios / Senior Animator

SEPTEMBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2020, BATH

Hand keyed animation on Funko's own IP and POP toy line adverts for clients including Marvel, DC, Disney.

- Working with the Creative department and Directors to bring their vision to life.
- Working with junior members of the team, offering support and feedback.
- Working in different styles of animation from realistic to a more 'snappy' cartoon style.
- Problem solving.

#### A Large Evil Corporation / Animator

SEPTEMBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018, BATH

Hand keyed animation on Funko's POP toy line adverts for clients including Marvel, DC, Disney.

- Working with the Creative department and Directors to bring their vision to life.
- Working with junior members of the team, offering support and feedback.
- Working to tight deadlines.
- Working independently and part of a team, handling projects through from start to finish.
- Problem solving.

#### Figment Productions LTD / Freelance animator (remote)

NOVEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2016, GUILDFORD

Creating humanoid/creature hand keyed animation for a Thorpe Park Virtual Reality ride.

- Taking direction.
- Problem solving.
- Working to tight deadlines.
- Being adaptable and looking for creative solutions to the brief.

#### **Hobbies & Pastimes**

I enjoy watching sport and I've always been a fan of PC gaming - first-person shooters and MMORPGs. When I can find the time, I enjoy running for exercise.